字幕转制｜天外生物
感谢原字幕制作者
谢谢各位
Thank you. Thank you.
也给你们自己点掌声，因为是你们付出的努力
But no, give yourselves a hand because it was your hard work
让这个机构旗下的“Yardsham Inlet”迈进最成功的一年
that gave Yardsham Inlet the best year in the history of this agency.
在我们将功劳拱手相让给我们的上司前
Before we let all that success go to our heads,
我们想让大家来个聚会，并再记起
we just thought we should get together and reconnect with the fundamentals
[主演：威尔·史密斯]
是什么带我们来到这一步
of what actually got us here.
为此，我将会交给
For that, I'm gonna turn it over
[片名：附属美丽]
我们产品的创办人，诗人及哲学家
to our resident poet philosopher of product.
反叛的指标
The rebel command of brand.
他是位让麦迪逊大道的人闻风丧胆的领袖
He's the guru who terrifies Madison Avenue.
我的拍档及知己
My partner, my better half,
霍华德·因莱特
Howard Inlet.
爱你
Love you.
噢，你的“原因”是什么？
Oh. What is your "why"?
你今早为什么起床？
Why did you even get out of the bed this morning?
你为什么吃你所吃的？
Why did you eat what you ate?
你为什么穿你所穿的？
Why did you wear what you wore?
你为什么来这里？
Why did you come here?
除了因为我会找人替代你的位置
Other than the fact that I would fire you and hire someone else
如果你不上班的话，但…
if you didn't show up for work, but...
我要说的不是这个，更重大的“原因”
Not that. The big "why."
我们会来这里工作绝对不是为了卖东西而已
We're certainly not here to just sell shit.
我们来这里
We are here
是去连系
to connect.
生命的重点是人们
Life is about people.
而广告的重点是
Advertising is about
点明我们的产品和服务
illuminating how our products and services
能够提升人们生活的质素
will improve people's lives.
那
Now,
我们如何办到？
how do we do that?
爱情
Love.
时间
Time.
死亡
Death.
这三个抽象的概念能够连系世上所有人
Now these three abstractions connect every single human being on Earth.
我们想要得到的事物
Everything that we covet,
我们害怕失去的事物
everything that we fear not having,
我们最终都会买的事物
everything that we ultimately end up buying
全都因为
is because at the end of the day
我们渴望爱情
we long for love,
我们希望有更多时间
we wish we had more time,
还有我们害怕死亡
and we fear death.
爱情
Love.
时间
Time.
死亡
Death.
我们就从那着手
Let's begin there.
[三 年 后]
这个砌了多久？
How long did this one take?
五天
Five days.
那其实很棒
That's pretty impressive.
- 可能他太早回来工作了  - 你开玩笑吗？
- Maybe he came back too soon.  - Are you kidding me?
这种日复一日的循例已经整整六个月了
It's been six months of this zombie routine.
我们不能再放纵他
We can't indulge this anymore.
尤其因为
Especially because
丹沃思金融公司快要跟我们解约了
we're getting fired by Danworth Financial.
什么？告诉我不是真的吧
What? You're kidding me.
- 不是吧，惠特  - 抱歉，什么？
- No, Whit, come on!  - I'm sorry, what?
我昨天才跟他们会面
But I just talked to them yesterday.
我知道，所有人都尽力隐瞒事实
I know. Everybody's been doing their best to cover,
但那整个户口都是建基于霍华德的人际关系
but that entire account is built on Howard's relationship.
我们一半的收入才是建基于霍华德的人际关系
Half our billings are built on Howard's relationships.
这下可惨了，简直是大灾难
This is a disaster. This is a disaster.
不，还不是
No. Not yet.
[宏盟集团：美国一家公司]
宏盟集团向我们提出每股十七块的提议
We have an offer from Omnicom for $17 a share...
- 我们不能这样做吧  - 但他们想要
- Oh, come on!  - ...but they want an answer
- 在新年前得到答覆  - 殊
- by New Year's.  - Shh.
坦白说，我们甚至不值一股十四块
Let's be honest, we're not worth $14 a share
如果我的拍档打算继续
if my partner takes a sabbatical
在他幻想的疯狂小镇中以骨牌之王自冠
as the local domino champion of Crazy Town.
惠特，那说得有点过份了
That's a little harsh, Whit.
抱歉，但那是现实
I'm sorry, but it's true.
西蒙，我正式赋予你接受宏盟集团的提议的权力
Simon, I am empowering you. Go make the deal with Omnicom.
我也想，但霍华德手持有表决权股份
I wish I could, but Howard controls the voting shares.
我会跟霍华德说，好了吗？
I'll deal with the Howard part, okay?
先准备文件草稿，西蒙
Just push the papers, Simon.
我依然不明白为何霍华德手持百分之六十有表决权股份
I still don't understand why Howard got 60% of the voting shares
而你只拥有百分之四十
and you only got 40.
因为我当时需要金钱去办妥我的离婚手续
Because I needed cash to settle my divorce
而霍华德让我卖给他一些股份，那帮了我很大的忙
and Howard did me a huge favor and let me sell him some.
即是说，如果你从没跟那刚入行的创作者有婚外情
So, if you never had an affair with some junior creative,
我们就不会落得如此下场？
we wouldn't be in this situation?
这是不准确又不公平的
Inaccurate and unfair
如果硬要让我一力承担
to put it squarely on my shoulders.
我只是在说事实
Well, I'm just pointing out the facts.
天啊，有人会不喜欢这香气吗？
Oh, my God. Don't you just love that smell?
等下
Wait. Stop.
闭下眼
Close your eyes.
用力吸
Breathe it in.
有没有让你回想起童年？
Doesn't that remind you of your childhood?
克莱尔，来这边
Claire, come here.
坐下吧，我有点事要告诉你
Come on, I got to tell you something.
什么？
What?
我最近一直试着改变我们现在的处境
I have been doing something about our situation
我觉得你有必要知道
that you need to know about.
你都做了什么？
What did you do?
我聘请了一个人
I hired someone.
你聘请了一个人？
You hired someone?
对，听着，以前艾萝依抓到我出轨
Yes. Look, when Eloise caught me cheating,
是因为她聘用了一位叫萨利·普赖斯的私家侦探
she used a private investigator named Sally Price.
她看上去像一个摩门教的老婆婆般不起眼
She's this woman who looks like a Mormon grandmother,
这给了她最好的隐藏身份
and it makes her very good at the whole stealth thing.
你聘请了那个让你离婚的女人？
You hired the woman who caused your divorce?
不，是我导致离婚的
No. I caused my divorce.
萨利·普赖斯只是将我的婚外情记录在案而已
Sally Price just documented it.
你还真不计前嫌
Wow. That was actually enlightened.
我们早已讨论过吧，我是个有深度的人
I have hidden depth. We've discussed this.
所以
So,
你为何聘用那个摩门教老婆婆？
why did you hire the Mormon grandmother?
因为我们需要记录霍华德现在的情况
Because we need to document what's going on with Howard.
我们需要显示他精神不够健全去作出决定
We need to show that he's not mentally fit to vote his shares.
不，我们不是真的要…
No. We're not really in that place where we're...
我们真的要变成这样的损友吗？
We're actually gonna be the people who would do that to a friend?
不是因为他一定不会卖他的股份
It's not that he won't sell,
而是因为他甚至不去谈论这个问题
it's that he won't even have a conversation about selling.
我试过接触他，跟他说话
I try to talk to him, I try to reach him,
而那就好像我跟他处在不同的次元一样
and it's like I'm not even in the same physical space with him.
他心不在焉
He's not there.
他的孩子去世了
His kid died.
那已经是两年前的事了，克莱尔
That was two years ago, Claire.
我们要怎样…
What are we gonna...
现在火烧眉毛
This is our lives at stake.
我们不再是小孩了，你当着我面跟我说
We're not kids anymore. You look me in the face
你愿意让过去十年你所付出过的
and tell me that you're willing to have everything you've worked for
付诸东流，我就不去做
for the last 10 years just evaporate.
这个私家侦探出色吗？
Is this PI good?
她抓到我出轨了
She caught me cheating.
奥斯卡也能做到
Oscar could have caught you cheating.
谁是奥斯卡？
Who the hell's Oscar?
我儿子
My son.
噢，那个奥斯卡？
Oh. That Oscar?
这个私家侦探不会找到任何
This private investigator isn't gonna find anything
违背道德的事
that'll pass for moral turpitude.
至少不会在霍华德身上找到
Not on Howard,
但如果她能引起他的法律资格的质疑
but if she can raise concern regarding legal capacity,
那我们就成事了
then we'll be in business.
我真的觉得我们别无选择
I do really think that we are out of other options.
他六个月来一直对心理辅导员爱理不理
You know, he terrorized the grief counselor for six months.
他完全不理我们远道从秘鲁取回来的死藤水萨满草药
He totally blew off the Ayahuasca shaman we flew in all the way from Peru.
而我们完全不能开解他
And our...Our intervention was a disaster.
我只是…
I just...
你的提议听起来不对
Look, uh, this doesn't feel right.
我明白
I know.
但从一个六岁的孩子患上绝症开始
But when something starts with a six-year-old dying,
没什么听起来是对的
nothing is gonna feel right.
他写了几封信
He writes letters.
信？什么信？
Letters? What kind of letters?
这可能是我生涯遇过最奇怪的一件事
This might be the strangest thing I have ever come across.
- 你有拿到那些信吗？ - 有
- You got the letters?  - Oh, yeah.
我们可以问下来历吗？
Can we ask you how?
花了我八百
Cost me $800
来造这把钥匙
to get this cut.
顺道说下
And just so you know,
从邮箱里直接偷取信件是犯法的
it's a federal offense to steal mail directly from a mailbox.
- 你可以收起…  - 对
- You could...  - Yeah.
- 共有三封信  - 写给谁的？
- So, three letters.  - Who are they to?
- 噢，不是“谁”  - 什么意思？
- Oh, not who.  - What do you mean?
霍华德不写信给人
Howard doesn't write letters to people.
他写信给事
He writes to things.
- 什么事？ - 时间
- What kind of things?  - Time.
爱情
Love.
死亡
Death.
那三个抽像的概念
The three abstractions.
致时间
"Time,
人们说你是一切伤害的良药
"they say you heal all wounds,
但他们不会说起你如何
"but they don't talk about how you destroy
将一切美好化为腐朽
"all that's good in the world.
如何将美丽的事物化作尘埃
"How you turn beauty into ash.
听着，你对我来说只不过是木化石
"Well, you're nothing more than petrified wood to me.
你是块不会分解的坏死组织
"You're a dead tissue that won't decompose.
你什么也不是
"You're nothing."
那不代表什么，我们不能利用这个吧？
That doesn't prove anything. We can't use that, right?
对，孩子们都写信给圣诞老人
No. I mean, kids write letters to Santa Claus,
那不代表他们疯了
it doesn't mean they're crazy.
不，这很治疗
No. This is therapeutic.
太悲伤了
It's so sad.
对，还有什么吗？
Yeah. Anything else?
他平常下班后，会到布鲁克林的一个宠物公园
Usually after work, he goes to a small dog park in Brooklyn,
即使他没有养狗
even though he doesn't own a dog.
就呆坐在那里
Just sits there for hours.
他会写信给狗吗？
Does he write letters to the dogs?
你开玩笑吗？
Are you serious?
我说，那就是我们想要的全垒打，对吧？
Well, that would be like the home run, right?
那是我们想要的有力证据
I mean, that's what we need.
- 他会吗？ - 我没有看到
- Does he?  - Not that I saw.
- 好吧，还有什么吗？ - 没有了，真的
- Okay. What else?  - That's it, really.
每天回到自己的寓所，非必要也不出门
Goes home to his apartment. Rarely leaves before morning.
没有网络，宽频，电话，什么也没有
No Wi-Fi, cable, phone. Nothing.
你是块不会分解的坏死组织
"You're a dead tissue that won't decompose."
霍华德？
Howard?
嗨，是克莱尔
Hey, it's Claire.
我经过路口的一间餐厅给你买了晚餐
I swung by that place down the street and got you some dinner.
有你喜欢的虾
It's that shrimp thing you like.
好吧，我把它放在这，以防你还没吃晚餐
Okay, I'm gonna leave it right here, in case you haven't eaten.
嘿，别再留下食物在那里
Hey, don't keep leaving the food there.
他不会吃的
He doesn't eat it.
噢，抱歉
Oh, I'm... I'm sorry.
还有他又迟了交房租
And he's late on his rent again.
他不应门，我也没有手提电话号码给他
He doesn't answer his door, and I don't have a working number for him.
他没有电话了
Yeah, he doesn't have a phone anymore.
他欠多少钱了？我写支票给你
Um, how much does he owe? I'll write you a check.
随便你
If that's what you want to do.
还有如果你不带走那晚餐
And, uh, if you're not doing anything with that shrimp...
我想说上周的球花甘蓝很美味
Broccoli rabe last week was delicious.
他来了
Here he is.
嘿，你的行李呢？
Hey, where's your stuff?
我本想发讯息给你，但妈妈要我致电给你
I wanted to text you, but Mom said I had to call.
说什么？
Text me about what?
然后巴里就我必须亲口跟你说
But then Barry said I had to tell you in person.
所以我们现在都要听巴里的提议吗？
Are we taking life advice from Barry now?
你…你想告诉我什么？
What are... What are you trying to tell me?
我不会过来跟你住
I'm not coming to stay with you.
我要跟巴里和妈妈一起去巴哈马
I'm going with Barry and Mom to the Bahamas.
不，等下
No, no. Wait, wait, wait.
午安
Hi.
你好吗？
How you doing?
我可以跟我的女儿
Can I get, like, five minutes, maybe a couple feet
独自相处一会吗？
just to have this conversation with my daughter?
谢谢
Thanks.
宝贝，我…
Honey, I got...
我把所有事都计划好了
I got all kinds of stuff planned.
我买了圣诞树
I got a Christmas tree for us.
那你真惨
Then sucks for you.
我买了汉密尔顿音乐剧的票
I got us tickets to Hamilton.
那真糟糕
Then sucks for Hamilton.
埃里森，那音乐剧一票难求
That's a tough ticket, Allison.
我已经看过了
I've already seen it.
你看过？跟你母亲和巴里？
You did? You saw that with Mom and Barry?
[小奥德尔·贝克汉姆：美式足球外接手]
和小奥德尔·贝克汉姆
And Odell Beckham Jr.
还有奥德尔贝克汉姆？
And Odell Beckham?
对
Yeah.
他是巴里的朋友之一
He's one of Barry's friends.
为什么？
Why?
为什么你不想跟我一起过节日？
Why don't you want to spend the holiday with me?
我想你了
I miss you.
因为我恨你
Because I hate you.
因为是个慈善家
Because you're a philanthropist.
因为你伤透了妈妈的心
Because you broke Mom's heart.
- 随性所欲的人  - 什么？
- Philanderer.  - What?
你想说的是随性所欲的人，不是慈悲家
The word you're looking for is philanderer, not philanthropist.
两者有点不同
They have a slightly different meaning.
你当然知道分别
Well, you would know.
我答应他们亲口告诉你，现在我做到了
Look, I agreed to tell you in person, and now I have.
嘿
Hey,
祝你圣诞快乐
have a good Christmas.
等下
Hold it.
嗨
Hey.
趁你在，来个快问快答吗？
So, rapid fire round while I got you?
骑士队作客
Cavs are in town.
在麦迪逊广场花园上演圣诞大战
Christmas showdown at the Garden.
我从没给过你门票
I never give your seat away.
现在只剩我一个去，但我们也可以一起去
I just go solo, but we could go.
到时候不理会大家也行
Don't even have to talk. Don't even have to look at each other.
可以像我们现在一样，然后专心看比赛
We can do just what we're doing right now and just watch the game.
就像旧时候一样
Be like old times.
好了，第二题
Right, number two.
我们快要失去丹沃思这个客户
We're gonna lose the Danworth account
因为那一直都是你打理的
because that's always been your relationship.
你也能想像得到，他们不再感受到你的用心
And they're not feeling the love, as you might imagine.
所以那就是无可避免的
So that's gonna happen.
随便吧
Whatever though,
因为我们有来自宏盟集团的提议，而且非常诱人
because we've got an offer from Omnicom, and it's real.
一股十七块
17 bucks a share.
请认真考虑，因为…
Please consider it, because...
对，我也知道
Yeah, yeah.
因为他们让我们继续现有的模式，而且没人会被辞退
Because they leave total creative control and they let everybody keep their jobs,
我知道你在意你的员工，因为你爱他们
which I know you care about, because you love these people.
非常愉快的谈心
Good talk.
[找寻你的精子捐赠者]
[是时候扩大你的家庭]
北京的人来了
The Beijing boys are here.
天啊，没有人会想要喝中国咖啡
Oh, God. No one wants Chinese coffee.
我们总要为他们卖广告
Well, we're selling it.
满州的玛琪雅朵咖啡，嗯
The Manchurian macchiato. Mmm.
我们在为什么选角？
What are we casting?
- 游轮  - 看，那才值得
- Cruise line.  - Now, see, that's good copy.
放下一切，寻找意义
"Shed your skin, find your life."
抱歉，应该是
Sorry, it's
当你放下一切才能找到生命意义
"Life is found when you shed your skin."
- 有所谓吗？ - 有，因为是我写的
- Does it really matter?  - Yes, because I wrote it.
原来如此，但我的较好
Oh, well, my way's better.
- 你真认为吗？哪里较好？ - 对
- Really? How?  - Yeah.
重温一下，你的是什么？
Well... Wait, what is your way?
当你放下一切才能找到生命意义
"Life is found when you shed your skin."
说中你脑里想的
Which, you know, kind of hits you here.
放下一切，寻找意义
"Shed your skin, find your life."
说到心窝里
Hits you here.
真的耶
That does hit me here.
对吧？
Right?
你可以随便拿去用
You can have it for free.
等下
Just, wait. Wait.
Wait.
- 嗨，弗兰克尔  - 什么事？
- Hey, Frankel.  - Yeah?
放下一切，寻找意义
"Shed your skin, find your life."
放下一切，寻找意义，知道了吗？
"Shed your skin, find your life." Everybody, okay?
知道
Got it.
她美化了它
She made it better.
嘿！
Hey!
别走
No, no, no.
嘿！
Hey, hey!
而你用这样的语气跟我说话
"And you talk to me in such tones
说得好像不是我把你带到这个世上
"as if it wasn't the breath in my lungs that gave you life."
- 你迟到了  - 抱歉
- You're late.  - Sorry.
说得好像不是因为我的灵光一触
"As if it wasn't a spark in my mind
才给予生命意义
"that gave that life meaning."
噢，你的舌头在动，你的嘴在吐字
"Oh, you move your tongue, you mouth syllables,
你的情感在翻腾
"you echo sentiment.
但你没有活过
"But you do not breathe."
你说火花？
"You speak of spark?
那简直是奢求
"That is richness.
因为你否认我们两个之间的火花
"For you deny the spark between us all.
那火花比起你那冷酷无情的火焰，简直是太阳般温暖
"A spark that is more a sun than the cold fire you claim.
而你竟形容我为年轻的冲动
"And you have called me a temporary madness.
一个邪恶的灵魂
"A vicious soul.
那
"Well,
抚心自问你想不想再见我一面
"then ask if you will see me just one more time."
你好
Hello?
Hi.
抱歉，我擅自走进这里
So sorry. I literally just wandered in,
我刚好看到最尾的部分
and I caught the tail end of that, and...
我可以表达我的赞赏吗？
Can I just say that was beautiful?
那是什么话剧？
What is... What is it?
只是些构思而已
It's just something we're trying to put together.
我…我很喜欢话剧，哪类型都喜欢
I just... I love theater. I see everything.
正式表演是什么时候？我会来的
So when's opening night? I'll be there.
直到我们筹得足够的钱前都不会有正式表演
There is no opening night until we get this money together.
- 你富有吗？ - 我离婚了
- You rich?  - Divorced.
你从刚才试镜就跟着我
You followed me from the casting session.
- 对，是的  - 是吧
- Absolutely, I did. Yes.  - Yeah.
我几乎看不到你，但你的红帽子帮了忙
I almost lost you, but the red hat helped.
我要说件有点突然的事
Hey, um, I'm gonna say something a little impulsive here,
听起来或者有点疯狂
maybe a little crazy,
我有件想要做的事
but, you know, I have something about to happen for me.
我正在跟别人商讨当中，但如果能成事
I'm in the middle of a deal that if it all comes together,
我就能资助你们
I'd be in a position to help.
那不是双赢的局面吗？
Well, now wouldn't that be lovely?
是，是件很好的事
It would. Be great.
而你，你刚才帮助了我
And you, you know, you fixed it.
所以，如果你想要刚才试镜的工作的话，我们可以让你来
So, we should get you back into casting if you want the gig.
抱歉，我甚至还没请教你的名字
Sorry, I don't even... I don't know your name.
- 我叫艾米  - 艾米
- Amy.  - Amy.
好吧
Okay. Well,
我会再来的，艾米
I'll be back, Amy. I'll be back.
我先走…
Mmm. And I'll be...
抱歉
Hmm. Sorry.
我太兴奋了
I was on the stage!
我会再来的
I'll be back.
你很有演技
You're good.
真有你的
Well done, you.
等下，现在都有《犯罪现场：克里夫兰》了吗？
Wait, they have a CSI: Cleveland now?
是全新一辑
It's a new show.
那些狼人
The werewolves,
他们在外面聚集
they're meeting out front
每晚都是
all hours of the night.
对，我也留意到
I heard them. Yeah.
我想他们…
I think they're...
我想他们正在投票选出组织的头目
I think they're voting on a new head of the syndicate.
但
But
我有个浣熊朋友，他是特种部队的一员
I got a raccoon friend. He's on the task force.
他在外面帮我放了个监听器在垃圾桶上
He put a bug out there for me by the trash cans.
我们将会录下他们所说的一切
We're gonna tape everything they say
并以诈骗、操纵和贿赂组织法控告他们
and we'll bust them on a RICO statute.
我不知道那是什么
I don't know anything about that.
嘿，我是你的儿子
Hey, I'm your son.
这我知道
I know that!
很好
Good.
我离开一下
I'll be right back.
我有个大胆的想法
Okay, I have kind of a wild idea.
你们听了很可能会取笑我
And I know you're gonna laugh at me,
但记住我们没有其他办法，所以听我说完
but remember that we're desperate and hear me out.
我的母亲自从中风后精神状态就不佳，对吧？
So, my mom hasn't been totally in her right mind since her stroke, right?
而我经常试着提醒她身边发生什么事
And I'm always trying to remind her what's actually going on
还有改正她的胡言乱语
and correct the, sort of, daffy things that she says.
而这样做令她感到不快乐，我也不知所措
And it upsets her, and it really stresses me out.
有段时间事情变得很麻烦
And it was pretty much just awful for a while.
然后，有人解开了我的心结
And then, someone said something very, very wise to me.
他们说：或者你不该强逼她听你的那套
They said, "Maybe you should stop trying to force your reality on her
而你试着跟她的思路走
"and just... Just go into her reality."
我以为你没钱去支付治疗费了
I thought you couldn't afford therapy anymore.
- 我是没有，那是我的优步司机说的  - 噢
- I can't. It was my Uber driver.  - Oh.
他完全正确
And he was totally right. Totally right!
当我开始照他说的做，所有事都轻松多了
As soon as I started doing this, everything got easier, you know?
我跟她的生活就变得很即兴
Our life is like this improvisational game.
她说些有的没的，而我就以她的方式回答她
She just... She says wackadoodle stuff, and I respond to it.
现在她过得很快乐，而我也颇喜欢这互动
And, uh, she's totally happy and I kind of have fun.
那让我想到一个人
And that made me think of something else.
好了
Okay.
[应为诊所之类]
以前我在“FBW”时
When I was at FBW,
我有个买兴奋药的户口
I had this account for a psychostimulant drug, right?
他们办了个什么筹款活动
And they went with some bullshit generic campaign,
我买了这套《西班牙裔美国人市场》
but I kept the Hispanic market.
看这个
Here, watch this. Okay.
那老师非常苦恼
So, the teacher is really stressing. He's saying, uh,
你们都在自己说话，不听我讲课
"Well, you talk all the time! You never listen!"
然后怪物进来
And then here comes the monster.
它说：不用这样的
"It doesn't have to be this way."
老师说：你是谁？
Teacher, "Who are you?"
怪物说：我就是你的愤怒啊
Monster, "I'm your anger, man."
老师回答
And the teacher says...
我不能再忍受你，你支配了我的生命
"I can't stand you, man. You dominate my life."
然后它回答：有个解决方法，朋友
And anger says, "There's a solution, my friend.
Docotrin，助你解决愤怒问题
"Docotrin, say goodbye to your anger."
你明白我想说的话？
Do you see where I'm going with this?
- 不太懂  - 好了，听着
- Not really.  - Okay, okay. Look, look.
我们不能让霍华德听我们的那套
We can't get Howard to deal with this reality that we need him to deal with.
他在写信给抽像的概念，完全不合逻辑
And he's writing letters to abstractions which makes no sense.
但他依然继续做
But... But he's doing it.
那么，如果我们跟他的思路
So, what if we just go into his reality
让那些抽像的概念回应他？
and we get those abstractions to answer him?
抱歉，我不明白
I'm sorry, I... I don't follow.
如果让爱情，时间，死亡实体化
What if Love, Time and Death show up in person
回应霍华德写给他们的信怎样？
and answer the letters that Howard's been writing to them?
在哪找爱情，时间，死亡？
How are Time, Love and Death gonna show up?
演员
Actors.
我们聘请演员扮演爱情，时间，死亡
We hire actors to be Love, Death and Time.
他们找到霍华德并跟他对质
They find Howard and they confront him.
所以你想让我们欺骗你的上司？
So, you want us to gaslight your boss?
- 抱歉，什么？ - 煤气灯下
- Huh? I'm sorry?  - Gas Light.
知道吗？是出话剧，然后拍成电影
You know? It was a play, then it was a movie.
那套煤气灯下？天啊
Gas Light? Oh, my God.
没有人会再看长过八秒钟的事了吗？
Does nobody ever watch anything longer than eight seconds anymore?
她的意思是，你想我们让他以为自己疯了？
What she's saying is you want us to make him think he's crazy?
不，目的不是这个
No, no, no. It's not about making Howard think he's crazy.
霍华德精神状态不佳，我们几个都知道
Howard's not in a good mental state, and we know that.
目的是让他人也知道
It's about underlining that fact so that other people can see it, too.
所以你想让我们跟他接触时演戏
Okay. So you want us to perform in this intervention,
而你们事后会资助我们的话剧？
and for that you're gonna finance our play?
- 对  - 正是
- That's it.  - Exactly.
对，我们会资助这个什么…
Yeah, we'll finance whatever...
这看起来像是货仓，但…
I mean, this looks like a storage facility, but...
好吧，其他演员，我们怎样？
Okay. Well, actors. What do we think?
- 不不不  - 噢，不是
- No. No, no, no.  - Oh, no.
听着
Listen, listen!
我们每人要求一万五
We take $15,000 each.
- 好吗？一万五  - 你疯了吗？
- Okay? $15,000.  - Are you completely out of your mind?
好吧，我们会帮你们
Okay, we'll do it.
以每人两万的报酬
$20,000, each.
不！我刚…你们才刚说一万五，我听到的
Uh-uh! I just...You guys just said 15. I heard you say 15.
- 我喜欢两万  - 我也是
- Mmm... I like 20.  - I like 20 as well.
两万真的太…有点过份了
Well, 20's just... I don't know, it's a little steep.
我打算给两千的，这些人很可能住在布鲁克林
I was thinking two. These guys probably live in Brooklyn.
- 他们月租六百  - 够了，停下吧
- They pay 600 bucks a month.  - Stop talking. Just stop.
你做得不错
You did a good job pulling them down.
这很可怕，这事完全不对
This is horrible. This is completely wrong.
不，艾米，这就是我们的工作，是演戏
No, Amy. This is the work. This is acting.
你没听到他们说这个人的孩子过世了吗？
Did you not hear them say that this man's lost his child?
有，那就是为何他选择向宇宙中寻找答案
Yes. And that's why he's reaching out to the cosmos for answers.
我们有幸扮演他想找的
Well, we get to be that cosmos.
所以你想我们运用这个男人的痛处，然后怎样？
So you want us to manipulate this guy's pain so that, what?
你们兑现？赚很多钱？
What, you cash out? You make a lot of money?
- 不！ - 当然不是！
- No!  - No, no, no, no!
你这样说听起来不对
That doesn't sound good when you put it that way.
- 这比看上去复杂得多  - 是吗？
- It's a lot more complicated than that.  - Is it?
我们都爱这个人
We love this man.
他不只是我们上司，他是朋友
And he's not just a boss, he's a friend.
霍华德是个有才华，创意和魅力的男人
Howard is a brilliant, creative, charismatic guy
他曾经是那样无所畏惧
who used to be fearless.
他曾经热爱他的生命，而现在，他恨透了生命
He used to love life, and right now, he hates it.
你们真的认为那样做能帮助他？
And you really think that this is gonna help him?
他失去了他的孩子
He lost his child.
而现在他不介意失去所有
And now he doesn't care if he loses everything else.
我们不能让这发生
We just can't let that happen.
我们要带他回来现实
We have to bring him back.
两万物有所值
$20,000's worth it.
- 我会付的  - 克莱尔！
- I'll pay for it.  - Claire!
我会自己交出钱来，我不在意
I'll pay for it. I'll pay for it myself. I don't care.
那规则呢？
So, what are the rules?
首先我们需要签合同
Well, first, we'd have to sign a confidentiality agreement.
确保你们不说出去，因为…
And make sure that you don't talk about it, 'cause...
我不是指法律条款
No, I don't mean the legal rules.
我指这出戏
I mean, the rules of the theatrical device.
例如，其他人也能看到我们吗？还是只有霍华德？
I mean, do other people see us, or only Howard?
- 对，其他人也能看到他们吗，惠特？ - 惠特？
- Yeah, do other people see them, Whit?  - Whit?
我猜…只有霍华德吧
I guess... I guess only Howard.
那就是我们想要的效果吧？
That's the effect we're looking for, right?
- 猜？ - 你猜？我…
- Guess?  - You guess? I mean...
抱歉，你到底有没有想清楚？
I'm sorry, have you thought this through?
- 当然有  - 没有
- Sure. Sure.  - No.
- 一定程度吧  - 不，我们没有
- I mean, to a degree.  - No, we haven't.
没有，惠特，停下，我们没有想清楚
No, we haven't, Whit. Shut up! Like... We haven't.
假设他们想要到酒吧里喝一杯呢？
For instance, what if they go into a bar and they want to order a drink?
他们如何能…
How can they do that if...
你近来有看见霍华德进酒吧吗？
Do you see Howard walking into a lot of bars these days?
随便吧，那不重要
Whatever. Doesn't matter.
- 那霍华德突然想去俱乐部呢？ - 他们是演员
- I mean, what if Howard goes clubbing?  - They're actors.
- 他们需要预备这种情况  - 够了够了
- They need to know hypothetically.  - Okay. Okay. Enough. Enough.
我们有选择被谁看见，何时看见的能力
We have the power to be seen by whomever we want, whenever we want.
- 那怎样？ - 不错，我喜欢
- How's that?  - I like that, I like that.
- 我说过他们是好演员  - 我喜欢
- I told you they were good.  - I like that, yeah.
我们该留给他们想
We should just leave it to them.
继续
Let's move on.
下一步呢？
What's next?
霍华德写了三封信，分别给爱情，时间和死亡
Howard wrote three letters to Love, Death and Time.
所以我想唯一的问题是，谁扮演哪个？
So, I guess the only question is who plays who?
选角，非常重要
Casting. Very important.
爱情
Love.
死亡
Death.
时间
Time.
很好，我们何时收到报酬？
Great. When do we get paid?
致死亡，你经过很多神话
"Dear Death, you travel with so much mythology,
给予很多伤痛，引起很多恐惧
"cause so much pain, inspire such fear.
但你对我来说纸老虎
"But you're a paper tiger to me.
你只是个可悲又没作为的中层管理人员
"You're just pathetic and powerless middle management.
你甚至没有权力去做一个简单的交易
"You don't even have the authority to make a simple trade."
你也看到，这不是位支持者写的信
As you can see, it's not exactly a fan letter.
对，死亡没有很多支持者
Yeah, well, Death doesn't have any fans.
我不明白你们为何这样做，因为这也算是解放
I don't understand why, because it's a liberation.
你还好吗？
Hey, you okay?
他上班，然后去宠物公园
He goes to work, and the dog park.
就这两个地方
And that's it.
好吧，这就是我会做的
Okay. So, here's how I'm gonna do it.
我会很愤怒的走上他面前
I'm gonna come to him angry.
非常愤怒的，像我们有问题要解决
Like, pissed off. Like, we got a problem.
不，别这样做
No, no, no. Don't do that.
他说我是木和坏死组织，他在呼唤我
He's calling me wood and dead tissue. He's calling me out.
这怎算呼唤你？
How's he calling you out?
是时间
Time.
[找寻一个更安全的捐赠者]
他在呼唤时间，而我就是时间
He's calling out Time, and I'm Time.
我不想你去跟霍华德对抗
Look, I don't want you antagonizing Howard.
你明白吗？
Do you get that?
但信里只写了“再见”
But the letter only consists of one word, "Goodbye."
看
Look.
致爱情，再见
"Dear Love, goodbye."
我到底要跟他说什么？
What am I even supposed to say to him?
那…
Um, it's...
这是封道别爱情的信，对吧？
It's a letter to Love saying goodbye, right?
- 对  - 那假如你走上前
- Yeah.  - So, what if you approach him,
然后说你拒绝接受？
and you refuse to accept that?
你说他不能那么容易就摆脱你
You say he can't get rid of you that easily.
告诉他
Tell him that
我们没有选择爱谁和被谁受的权利
we don't get to choose who we love and who loves us back.
告诉他你在他之中
Tell him that you're within him,
你在万物之中，无论他喜欢与否
you're within everything, whether he likes it or not.
如果他接受了
And if he accepts that,
那可能… 我不知道
then maybe... I don't know.
他可能找回他的生存意义
Maybe he gets to find his life again.
他们会悲伤
They grieve.
狗只们
Dogs.
他们会悲伤，而且了解死亡
They grieve, and they fully understand death.
你说我是纸老虎
You called me a paper tiger.
在你给我的信当中
In the letter you wrote me.
你说我可悲
You said I was pathetic.
嗯
Mmm.
你不记得了吗？
You don't remember?
你说了一堆中层管理人员
You went on about middle management,
做交易，纸老虎
making a deal, paper tiger.
霍华德，那才过不久
Oh, Howard, it wasn't that long ago.
你从哪拿到的？
Where did you get that?
- 你是谁？ - 你写给谁？
- Who are you?  - Who did you write the letter to?
我写给死亡
I wrote the letter to Death.
很高兴认识你，我肯定你被迷倒了
Nice to meet you. Charmed, I'm sure.
不
No.
我明白
I know, I know.
人们经常写信给宇宙
People write letters to the universe all the time.
大部份都没有得到答覆
Most don't get a personal response.
但你有，因为我只想告诉你，你错了
But you are, because I just wanted to tell you that you're wrong.
我不是什么没作为的中层管理人员
I'm not some powerless middle management
- 还有只跟从指令  - 小姐
- just following orders.  - Miss...
我不想做交易，是我决定的
You see, I didn't want to make the trade. It was my call.
我不想听你说
I don't want this. I don't want this.
我没有对你的工作指指点点
Now, I don't tell you how to do your job.
所以我也希望你别教我如何工作
So, I'd appreciate it if you didn't tell me how to do mine.
那个男人在跟谁说话？他看起来有点怪
Who's that man talking to? He looks kind of weird.
别担心，有时候人们做些不能理解的事
Don't worry about that. Sometimes people are silly.
你看，他们看不到我存在，直到轮到他们
You see, they don't see me till it's their time.
没事的，霍华德，还没轮到你
Oh, it's okay, Howard. It's not your time yet.
我只想交还你这个
I just wanted to return this
并且解决我们之间的恩怨
and clear things up between us.
我真的是死亡，霍华德
I really am Death, Howard!
他信了
He believed me.
我告诉你，他信了
I'm telling you he believed me.
- 真棒  - 那非常精彩
- That's amazing.  - I mean, that was spectacular.
因为没有第二次机会
Because there was no safety net, you see.
[格罗托夫斯基了：导演]
那真的太格罗托夫斯基了
That... That... That was Grotowski.
[斯特拉·阿德勒：演员]
- 那简直是斯特拉·阿德勒  - 对
- That was pure Stella Adler!  - Ah!
- 谢谢你给予我这个机会  - 对
- Thank you. Thank you for the opportunity.  - Yes.
- 你真是个好人  - 不成问题
- You are a kind man.  - Oh, not a problem.
- 他信了，我告诉你  - 我不会这么肯定
- He believed me, I'm telling you.  - I wouldn't go that far.
他需要这个，我可以从他的眼睛里看到
But he needed it. I could tell. I could tell in his eyes.
那个女人和小男孩是谁？时机很棒
Who was that woman and that little boy? That was incredible.
那是我们的私家侦探和她的孙子
Oh, that was our private investigator and her grandson.
真的？她有说我的演出怎样吗？
Oh, really? And did she say anything about me?
她说你很好
She said you were good. She said really good.
好？什么意思？像…
"Good"? What do you mean? Good like...
像卷心菜一样好还是什么？
You mean good like cabbage is good, or what?
不不，她…出色
No, no. She... Great.
她说：她将不可能化为可能
She said, she said, "She made the impossible possible."
我该给你钱
I should be paying you.
他们当时告诉我特雷弗已收拾好他的包袱
They told me that Trevor had packed his little suitcase,
他说他要回家了
that he said he was going home.
我愤怒极了
I was furious.
但他在睡，所以我没有跟他说话
But he was sleeping, so I couldn't talk to him.
什么样的护士会答应一个正在慢慢死去的五岁小男孩
I mean, what nurse promises this dying five-year-old little boy
他能回家？
he could go home?
他几乎没剩多少白血球
He barely had any white blood cells left.
他很脆弱
He was so fragile.
谁能这么残忍呢？
And who could be so cruel?
谁能对他撒谎呢？
Who could do that?
所以当然，我失控了
So, of course I'm frantic.
我对职员大声责骂，只想寻根究底
I am shouting at the staff, trying to get to the bottom of it.
特雷弗终于醒了
Well, Trevor finally wakes up
我走上前
and I go to him.
他的蓝色包包还放在床尾
You know, his little blue suitcase was still at the edge of the bed, right.
我看着他并问
So, I look at him and ask,
谁跟你说的，宝目？
"Who said that to you, sweetie?
谁说你可以回到我们的房子？
"Who said that you could come back to our house?"
你知道他怎样回答吗？
You know what he says?
没有人，妈妈
"Nobody, Mommy.
我不是回我们的房子
"I'm not going back to our house.
我是回我所属之处
"I'm going home."
他四小时后过世了
He died four hours later.
你好
Hello.
Hi.
你在找“小翅膀支援团队”吗？
Are you looking for Smallest Wings Support Group?
嗯…
Um...
- 对  - 你是？
- Yes.  - And you are?
- 嗯，霍华德  - 霍华德
- Um, Howard.  - Howard.
进去坐下吧
Come on in. Have a seat.
你失去了孩子吗，霍华德？
Did you lose a child, Howard?
对
Yeah.
- 男还是女？ - 啊…
- Boy or girl?  - Uh...
女儿
A girl.
那她的名字是？
And what was her name?
没关系，霍华德
No, it's okay. Howard.
你不必回答
You don't have to answer.
你甚至不需要说话
You don't even have to talk, okay?
可以留下吗？
You stick around?
拜托？
Please?
好了
Okay.
谢谢你的分享
Thank you so much for sharing.
我们都很感谢
We really appreciate it.
谢谢
Thank you.
有人想要分享什么吗？
Does anybody have anything else they'd like to say?
- 你今晚为何打算进来？ - 嗯？
- So, why'd you decide to come in tonight?  - Hmm?
我以前看过你站在外面
Yeah, I've... I've seen you outside.
我早晚打算邀请你进来
I was gonna come out one night and invite you in,
但我猜我不想暴露你的隐藏位置
but I guess I didn't want to blow up your spot.
暴露我的隐藏位置？
Blow up my spot?
- 对  - 你不想打乱我的节奏？
- Yeah.  - You didn't want to mess up my jam?
正是
Exactly.
你叫什么？
What's your name?
我是玛德琳
I'm Madeline.
很高兴认识你
Nice to meet you.
我女儿叫奥利维亚
My daughter's name was Olivia.
她因为一种叫胶质母细胞瘤的罕有脑癌而过世
She died of a rare form of brain cancer known as Glioblastoma Multiforme,
或简称“GBM”
or GBM for short.
她当时六岁
She was six years old.
你的女儿叫什么，霍华德？
What was your daughter's name, Howard?
好吧
Okay.
不要紧，别回答，我不想折磨你
Fine. Don't answer. I'm not gonna torture you.
谢谢
Thank you.
- 是因为节日吗？ - 嗯？
- Was it the holidays?  - Mmm?
你今晚进来的原因
Why you decided to come in tonight.
有很多第一次来的人都是在节日期间
We get a lot of first-timers during the holidays.
- 不，不是因为这个  - 那为什么是今晚？
- No, that's not it.  - Then why tonight?
我想…
Uh, I guess...
我…
I'm, uh...
我在试着解开心结
I'm trying to fix my mind.
你失去了孩子，霍华德
You lost a child, Howard.
你的心结永远都会在
It'll never be fixed.
我希望你会再来
I hope you come back.
嗨
Hey.
这是签妥了的合约和保密协议
Signed contracts and confidentiality agreements.
- 太好了，谢谢  - 所以他有说什么吗？
- Oh, great. Thank you.  - So, did he say something?
谁啊？霍华德？
Who, Howard?
- 不幸的，没有  - 他信了
- No. Unfortunately, he didn't.  - He believed it, I'm telling you.
- 那真是太好了  - 或许你该再派我去了
- Oh, that's good.  - Maybe you should send me in again.
而不是拉菲，他太急躁了
Not Raffi. Raffi's too impetuous.
还有艾米，她太感情用事
And Amy, she's just so emotional.
除了我，还有谁？
After me, what is there?
他共写了三封信
Well, he did write three letters.
但死亡比时间重要多了
But Death is so much more vital than Time.
- 对  - 死亡给予时间意义
- Right.  - Death gives Time all of its value.
或许全都该由我扮演
Maybe... Maybe I should play all the parts.
你知道现时人口统计中的新任父母的数字比以往高吧？
You know the highest margin demographic is new parents now?
他们制造出一条算法
Target actually invented an algorithm
去推算他们的女性客户何时会怀孕
to predict when their female customers were gonna get pregnant.
你之前说过你不适
You said before that you weren't okay.
你患病了吗？
Are you sick?
对
I'm sick.
你可以说我的病情非常严重
You could say, uh, I'm very sick.
你要死了吗？
You're dying?
每个人都在死去
Everyone's dying.
对，但你时日无多
Yeah, but you're doing it now.
西蒙，西蒙
Simon. Simon.
来吧，告诉我，是什么病？有什么不对劲了？
Come on, tell me. Tell me. What is it? What's wrong?
有什么不对劲？
What's wrong?
就是我病情恶化了
What's wrong is that I came out of remission
在我儿子出生前的两周
two weeks before my son was born.
是我
What's wrong
每天都要装作我还很健康
is that I'm running a marathon every day pretending to be healthy.
那就是不对劲的地方
That's what's wrong.
你有跟谁说过吗？
Have you told anyone?
没有？
You haven't?
没有，就一个我几乎不认识却又不断质问我的女演员
No, just some pushy actress that I don't really know.
什么病？
What is it?
是多发性骨髓瘤
It's multiple myeloma.
我十六岁时发病，二十五岁又重发
I fought it when I was 16, and then again when I was 25.
它从没离开过
It just never went away.
反而组织起来变得更强
Instead it regrouped and got stronger.
所以没法医治？
So, the war's over?
对
Yeah, war's over.
你的身后事处理好了吗？
Are your affairs in order?
没有
My affairs are not in order.
所以我聘请了你
That's why I hired you.
我要离开我的家人已经够坏了
It's bad enough that I'm leaving my family.
我不会让他们之后身无分文
I'm not gonna leave them penniless.
他信了我
He believed me.
霍华德
Howard.
他信了我
He believed me.
抱歉，别碰
Hey. Excuse me. No, don't touch that.
我不明白骨牌
I don't understand dominoes.
没有计分牌，或者一个篮框
There's no board to play them on, or basket to throw them into.
对
Right. Um...
我想你去错地方了
I think you might be in the wrong place.
不，我没去错，霍华德
No, I'm in the right place, Howard.
对吧
Mmm. Yeah.
致时间，人们说你是一切伤害的良药
"Time, they say you heal all wounds,
但他们不会说起你如何将一切美好化为腐朽
"but they don't talk about how you destroy all that's good in the world.
如何将美丽的事物化作尘埃
"How you turn beauty into ash."
那真是一派胡言，霍华德
Now that's some bullshit, Howard.
如果爱情是创造而死亡是破坏
If Love is creation and Death is destruction,
我就只是他们两者之间
I'm just a terrain in between.
你不了解时间，没有人了解时间
You don't understand Time. No one understands Time.
爱因斯坦几乎弄清，他说我是幻想
I mean, Einstein came close when he said I was an illusion.
霍华德？嘿
Howard? Hey. Uh...
听着，我很肯定你会回答“不”
Listen, I'm sure it's a "no"
但奥奈达服装公司要求你在会议出现
but Oneida Apparel asked that you be in the media buy meeting.
很抱歉我阻碍了你
I'm sorry to just barge in.
问她
Ask her.
问她能不能看到我
Go ahead. Ask her if she can see me.
我不会在会议出现
I'm not gonna be in the meeting.
嗯哼
Mmm-hmm.
他们坚持要我问你
Well, they insisted I ask.
他们很可能会跟我们解约，所以…
I mean, they're probably gonna fire us, so...
好吧
Okay.
- 太好了  - 我去
- Awesome.  - Yes.
好吧
Okay.
晚点见
See you later.
你可以拿回这个，霍华德
You can have this back, Howard.
你到底为何写信给我？
Why did you write me anyway?
是因为你需要我
You wrote me because you need me.
不
No. Um...
我不需要你，明白吗？
I don't need anything from you, okay?
你们都喜欢埋怨
You all like to bitch and complain.
不够时间
"There isn't enough time."
人生苦短
"Life is short."
看，白发都出来了
"Oh, here, the gray hairs are coming in."
一天其实长得很
You know, a day is long as hell.
我非常充沛，我是份礼物
I'm abundant. I'm a gift.
即使现在你站在这里抱怨
Even while you're standing here talking shit,
也是份礼物，而你浪费了
I'm gifting you, and you're wasting it.
用在什么上了？
On what?
这是什么？
I mean, what is this? Huh?
嘿！
Hey, hey!
你知道吗
You know,
我才应该写信埋怨
I should be the one that's writing angry letters.
那是我做过最差劲的一件事
That was the worst thing I've ever done.
那是我做过最好的一件事
That was the best thing I've ever done.
你刚才说什么爱因斯坦？
What was that thing you said about Einstein in there?
爱因斯坦说时间是固执又坚持的幻像
Einstein called time a stubbornly persistent illusion.
那究竟是什么？
What's that even mean?
时间不是从一月走到十二月
Time doesn't go from January to December,
或从早到晚
or from noon to midnight.
那只是人类的观点
You know, we all just make it that way in our heads.
荒谬至极
That's absurd.
你试着跟一个在婚礼上迟到的人说这个
Try telling that to a person who's an hour late to a wedding
或是跟一个刚被判二十年监牢的人说
or was just sentenced to 20 years in jail.
或是一个快更年期的女人
Or someone fighting a baby clock.
我们其实不需要交心
We really don't need to have this conversation, ever.
无论如何
Anyway, just...
你今天做得很好
Yeah, wanted to say great job today.
只是个固执的幻像，克莱尔
Just a stubborn illusion, Claire.
你还有很多时间
You have all the time in the world.
你是九点
You're nine!
"You're nine."
你好
Hi.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
你一定在开玩笑吧
You gotta be friggin' kidding me.
我在用餐
I'm eating.
你说了再见，而那…
You said goodbye, and that...
我们没有选择爱谁和被谁爱的权利
We don't get to choose who we love or who loves us back.
那代表你只要还在世就无法对我做什么
And that means you're powerless to me as long as you're alive
因为我是生命的基本
because I'm the fabric of life.
我在你当中，我在万物当中
I'm within you. I'm within everything.
霍华德
Howard,
如果你能接受，那可能…
if you can accept that, then maybe...
我不知道，但你可能可以重新过活
I don't know, but maybe you get to live again.
我失败了
I completely screwed it up.
我太悲哀和充满了歉意
I was weepy and apologetic.
我认为爱也可以是那样
Well, I think love can be weepy and apologetic.
我想我最后还算可以
I think I was better at the end.
嘿，我肯定你尽力了
Hey, hey. I'm sure you were great.
你真好
You're sweet.
我可以吻你吗？
Can I kiss you?
你不需要将它性化
You don't have to sexualize it.
我可以不性化地吻你
I can kiss you without sexualizing it.
真的，我试过没有性爱的性
Seriously, I've had sex without sexualizing it.
你应该停在“好”的阶段，惠特
You should take "sweet", Whit.
算是升职了
It's a promotion.
无法抗拒才算是升职
"Irresistible" would be a promotion.
他信了
He believes it.
你怎知道？
How could you tell?
我从他的眼中看到
I could tell by his eyes.
很好，但除了你没人看到
That's great, but no one else has seen it
而那终究是我们的目的
and that's ultimately what we need to have happen.
我们认为你们该再接触他
We think if you would engage with him
- 在公众场合  - 很好了
- one more time, um, in public.  - Great.
但这次试着…
But this time try to...
但你们需要挑衅让他有很大的举动
But you need to provoke a strong visible reaction.
为什么？
Why?
因为我们的私家侦探会录影
Because our private investigator's gonna capture it on video.
并用来做证据
And we're gonna use it as evidence.
那就好像拍电影
It'll be like being in a movie.
除了会后期加工将你们除去
Except you'll be digitally removed.
不要
No.
什么？
Sorry?
太激烈了
This is too intense.
抱歉，我不能继续
Um, I'm sorry. I can't be a part of this.
艾米，演戏里没有什么叫“激烈”
Amy, there is no "too intense" in acting.
你想被爱还是被记住？
Do you wanna be loved or do you wanna make an impact?
[诺埃尔·科沃德：演员]
这不是诺埃尔·科沃德
I mean, this isn't Noel Coward.
[契诃夫：短篇小说家]
这是…契诃夫
This is... This is Chekhov.
这是荒谬！
This is horrible!
你知道的
The... You know,
你曾经跟他一起创办那间机构吧，惠特？
you did start the agency with him, didn't you, Whit?
克莱尔，他是你的导师
And, Claire, he was your mentor.
西蒙，他让你成为持有人
And, Simon, he gave you part ownership in a business
而他完全没有必要
when he absolutely didn't have to.
我跟她说过了点我们的事
I may have told her a few things...
我们…
when we were...
抱歉，这不能接受
I'm sorry, this is horrible.
我不能…参与其中，谢谢
I... I can't...No, I can't be a part of this. Thank you.
- 抱歉，谢谢了  - 艾米，别走
- Sorry. Thanks.  - Amy, no.
艾米
Amy.
艾米，别走
Amy. No.
她太多心了
Oh, she's so passionate, you know.
艾米！
Amy!
抱歉，她会回来的
I'm so sorry. She will be back.
但如果她不回来
But if she isn't, um,
我会介入，我很熟悉爱情
I'll step in. I do know all about love.
艾米！
Amy!
我错过了什么？
What'd I miss?
人们都在为他们死去的孩子们哭
People crying because their kids died.
有种病叫丧失性幻觉
Uh, there's a thing called bereavement hallucinations.
对
Yes.
Right. Um. Okay.
所以…
So, uh...
我查了一下
I looked them up.
有点东西我明白，我不睡觉的
And here's the thing. I don't sleep.
是的
Okay.
不太睡觉
Like, not a lot.
我会睡
I mean, I sleep.
但可能一星期只睡六，七小时
But I get six or seven hours a week.
现在我回想起来，那可能就是为什么…
Now that I think about it, that's probably why...
什么为什么？
Why what?
我在谈话
I'm having conversations.
我指，谈话
I mean, conversations.
对
Okay.
没关系了
It's okay. Never mind. Um...
- 霍华德？ - 是
- Howard?  - Yeah.
你想跟我谈话吗？
You wanna have a conversation with me?
是
Uh, yes.
所以我可以假设你是那百分之七十九之一？
So, I assume you're a part of the 79%?
嗯？
Mmm?
百分之七十九夫妇丧子后会离婚
Of couples who get divorced after losing a child.
对
Yeah.
对，我也是
Yeah, me too.
你还爱她吗？
Do you still love her?
我甚至已经不知道什么是爱
I don't even know what love is anymore.
你还爱他吗？
Do you still love him?
我们从没停止爱过对方
We never fell out of love.
至少，我不认为，只是…
At least, I don't think so. It's just...
我们可以…
We can...
我们办妥了离婚手续的那天，他给了我这个
The day our divorce was final, he sent me this.
如果我们可以重新相遇一次就好了
"If only we could be strangers again."
现在我们是
Now we are.
这是他做过最浪漫的举动
The most romantic gesture he ever made.
所以，回答你刚才的问题
So, to answer your question,
对
yes,
我还爱着他
I still love him.
你什么意思
What did you mean
当你说你在谈话？
when you said you were having conversations?
对
Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah.
跟谁谈话？
Conversations with who?
不是谁
It's not "who."
那真是…
It's really... It's...
你会以为我疯了
You're gonna think I'm crazy.
说一下
Try me.
我可以带你去看吗？
Um, can I show you?
不会分解的坏死组织
"Dead tissue that won't decompose."
他那时就坐在这里
He was sitting right here.
就是个说话刻薄又骄傲的小流氓
Just a mean, little, arrogant thug.
他是第一个出现的吧？
And he was the first one that appeared, right?
不，死亡先出现
Uh, no. Death came first.
她在宠物公园找到我
She met me in the dog park.
所以死亡是个女人？
Oh, so Death is a "her"?
对，原来死亡是个白种婆婆
Uh, yeah. It turns out Death is an elderly white woman.
什么交易？
What was the trade?
你说死亡不跟你做交易
You said Death wouldn't make the trade.
什么意思？
What does that mean?
当我们意识到…
When we realized our...
我的女儿在死去，我祈祷
My daughter was dying, I prayed, uh...
不是向上帝或者宇宙，而是向死亡
Not to God or the universe, but to Death.
我提出一个交易
I offered a trade.
带走我
Take me,
留下我的女儿
leave my daughter.
但死亡不想交易，所以…
But she didn't wanna make the trade, so...
所以谁赢了那回合？
So, who won that round?
你还是瓷器？
You or the porcelain?
瓷器，它从未输过
Porcelain. Porcelain's undefeated.
抱歉，我以为所有人都走了
I'm sorry about that, I thought everyone left.
对，他们走了，但我还没
Yes, they did. But I'm here to close up.
很好
Good.
你需要我帮手带你回家吗？
You need help getting home?
不，我没事
No. I'm fine.
我很好
I'm... I'm good.
我搜寻了你
I Googled you.
- 你搜寻了？ - 对
- You did?  - Yeah.
天啊
Oh, God.
从一无所有
You came from nothing.
捱过杜克大学
You put yourself through Duke,
娶了个美丽的女人
you married a wonderful woman,
是个很有爱心的父亲
you're a loving father.
你活得不错，你活过了
So, you lived well. You lived right.
但朋友，你现在这样是不对的
But, my friend, you're not dying right.
你打算告诉我如何死吗？
Are you gonna tell me how to die?
你跟你的家人说过了吗？
Have you told your family yet?
- 没  - 你这不是在帮他们
- Mmm-mmm.  - You're not helping them.
你只是在否定他们得知真相的权利
You're just denying them what is rightfully theirs.
是吗？什么真相？
Yeah? And what's that?
痛苦？萎缩？疾病？
Pain? Atrophy? Disease?
对，正是
Yes. Yes.
全部都是
All of it.
还有告别的机会
And the chance to say goodbye.
还是专注演出吧
Stick to acting.
好了
Okay.
我有件我从没跟别人说过的事
I have something that I haven't told anyone.
不关于信或天使或者什么
It doesn't involve letters or angels or anything like that,
但它对我意义重大
but it means something to me.
他们当时在准备告别奥利维亚
They were preparing Olivia to say goodbye.
我的丈夫在停车场尝试让我母亲冷静下来
And my husband was trying to calm my mother in the parking lot
因为她完全不能接受
because she lost it.
所以我当时独自一人
So I was alone
坐在
and I was sitting there
布碌仑玛摩利医院的等候室
in the waiting room at Maimonides Hospital.
那里有个女人坐在我旁边
And there was this woman who sat next to me.
她问我我要失去谁了
And she asked me who I was about to lose.
我告诉了她
And I told her.
然后她看着我并说
And she looked at me and she said,
记着留意
"Just be sure to notice
附属的美丽
"the collateral beauty."
她…
I mean, she...
她说得很随口
She said it so casually.
一墙之隔
In the next room,
我的六岁女儿正在被拆下维持生命的机器
my six-year-old daughter was being taken off life support.
而那女人说附属的美丽
And this woman says "collateral beauty."
人们都不知道那种时候该说什么
People don't know what to say in those moments.
不，她知道
No, she did.
只是当时我没有意会到
I just didn't get it at the time.
那不是因为同情我或者气氛尴尬
See, it wasn't said out of sympathy or awkwardness.
那是经验之谈
It was from experience.
约一年后
About a year later,
有些事开始发生在我身上了
something started to happen to me, you know.
我会在街上或地下铁走着
I would be walking or on the subway, whatever,
然后突然大哭起来
and I would just burst into tears.
但那不是为奥利维亚流下的泪
But these weren't Olivia tears.
那是因为有东西重生了而留
These were tears born from something else,
因为对一切深刻的连系而留
from this kind of profound connection to everything.
然后我意识到了
And I realized
那就是附属的美丽
it was the collateral beauty.
那真是…
I mean, there's...
世上没有一种叫附属的美丽
There's no such thing as collateral beauty.
有的，霍华德
There is, Howard.
真的有
There really is.
虽然那不会让她活过来
It'll never bring her back.
也不会让我忘掉一切
And it will never ever make it okay.
但我保证你，它真的存在
But I promise you, it's there.
好吧
Okay.
你需要跟他们说话，霍华德
You need to talk to them, Howard.
听着
Look, um...
很感谢你分享的故事
Appreciate your story,
但我没有感觉到这附属美丽
but I'm not really feeling the "collateral beauty" thing.
我不在乎
I don't care!
对他们呼喊，跟他们说道理，挑战他们
Yell at them, reason with them, challenge them.
就试着接触他们
Just engage!
我想这一切都是错误的
I think this was a mistake.
- 你好  - 你好
- Hi.  - Hi.
你在这里做什么？
What're you doing here?
碧姬告诉我在这里可以找到你
Uh, Brigitte told me this is where I could find you.
当然吧
Of course she did.
我们可以走走，聊聊天？
Could we just go and talk somewhere for 15 minutes by ourselves?
我其实在工作，我在排练
I'm... I'm actually working. I'm rehearsing right now.
- 你在这里也排练？ - 对
- You're rehearsing here, too?  - Yeah.
你同时间在做多少工作？
How many projects are you doing at the same time?
现时的话三件
I'm currently doing three.
三件，哗
Three. Wow.
- 对  - 一定很忙
- Yeah.  - That's really busy.
那我们哪有时间去吃晚餐？
How are we gonna fit a dinner date in?
惠特…
Whit...
听着，真的
Listen, listen, listen. Seriously...
我想让你重新考虑你昨晚所说的
I have to ask you to reconsider what you said last night.
我们需要你再一次的帮忙
We need you one more time.
就一场戏
Just give us one more scene.
我不会去的
I am out.
艾米，你想要…
Amy, what do you...
等下，我可以说什么？你想要…
Wait, what can I say? What do you...
事成我会给你十万，不是两万
I'll give you $100,000. Not 20, 100.
你没有十万
You don't have $100,000.
对，我跟我母亲一起住
You're right. I live with my mother.
但这会成事的，而完成后，我会有很多钱
But this is gonna work, and when it does, I'll have much, much more.
我会给你一百万
And I'll give you a million.
- 我不想要你的钱  - 我真的会
- I don't want your money.  - I really will.
我不想要你的钱
I do not want your money.
你知道吗，我从不想要你的钱
Do you know, I've actually never wanted your money.
我到底要说什么才能让你回来？
What can I say to get you to do this?
因为有太多紧急的事要处理，你甚至不会想到
Because there's so much more at stake here, you have no idea.
噢
Oh.
你有个女儿吧？
You have a daughter, right?
对
Yeah.
我有说过吗？
Did we talk about that?
告诉我她出生的那天你的感受
Tell me what it was like the day that she was born.
什么？
What?
对你而言那是什么感受？
What it felt like for you.
很可怕
Uh, it was scary.
非常可怕，我完全不知所措
It was very scary. I was terrified.
但当他们让我抱着她
But then they gave her to me
我感觉到了前所未有的感觉
and I had the most amazing sensation run through me.
那…我不能说…
It... I can't...
什么？说完它
What? Finish it.
那听起来很愚蠢
It sounds... It's goofy.
不，那听起来不愚蠢
No, it doesn't sound goofy.
这其实是我第一次感觉到
Do you know, actually, this is the first time that I felt
我对你的事有兴趣
any attraction towards you, whatsoever.
- 真的吗？ - 是
- Really?  - Yes.
我看着她，然后我…
I looked at her and I...
我意识到我没有感受到爱意
I realized that I wasn't feeling love.
我成为了爱
I had become love.
虽然她现在不再跟我说话
She doesn't talk to me now, though.
她把离婚责怪于我，她还在生我气
She blames me for the divorce, and so she's angry at me.
而…
And...
这是我值得的下场
I deserve it.
我跟你做个交易
I'm gonna make you a deal.
如果你能将这些
If you can take all of this,
坦白又积极的决心
frankly, aggressive determination
还有非凡的开放态度
and extraordinary openness
用在赢回你女儿的心上
and use it on winning your daughter back,
那我就帮你们
then I'll do it.
约定了
It's a deal.
你没感受到吗？
See, you don't feel that?
放开我
Oh, wow. Give me my hand back.
你感受到的吧？
You feel that though, right? You feel it?
- 那就是火花  - 再见，惠特
- That's sparks.  - Goodbye, Whit.
那就是火花
That's what that is.
[律师信]
[关于宏盟集团，尽快联络]
嗨，怎样了？
Hey! What's up?
- 什么？ - 你有点话要说吗？
- What?  - You got something to say?
你有点想要说的话吧？
You got something you wanna say?
对，我有很多事想告诉你
Oh, yeah. I got a lot of things I'd like to say to you.
说出来啊！
Well, say it. Say it!
你就只会浪费时间
See, you just waste time.
我给予了你这份礼物，而你就白白浪费它
See, I give you a gift and you just waste it!
我不在乎时间
I don't care about time.
这是监禁
This is a prison sentence!
我不想要你的所谓礼物
I don't want your gift!
因为你拿走了她的时间
Because you took hers.
噢，又来了
Oh, come on.
你是来带我走的吗？
Are you here to take me?
不，霍华德，我来这里跟你一起坐车
No, Howard. I'm here to ride the F train with you.
好吧
Oh, okay.
我说，有对龙凤胎在肚里
So, there are these two twins in a womb, a boy and a girl.
你在说笑话吗？
You telling a joke?
不，这是个故事
No, no. It's a story.
这对双胞胎非常快乐
So, these twins are happy.
有食物，又温暖，他们感到很安全
They're fed, they're warm, they feel safe.
但他们越来越大，不够位置
But they're outgrowing their space
他们意识到这不是办法
and they realize this can't go on forever.
所以他们开始想
So they start thinking,
“接下来会怎样？
"What comes next?
如果变得又冷又寂寞呢？
"What if it's cold or lonely?
如果我们不再在一起呢？
"What if we're not together?
如果这根本什么都不是呢？”
"What if there's nothing at all?"
然后那女孩看着脐带
So, then the girl looks at the cord.
那条一直给他们养分的脐带
This cord that has fed them, has nourished them,
那条他们根本不可能猜透的脐带
this cord that they can't possibly conceive
很可能连系在任何东西上
could be attached to anything else.
然后她说
And she says,
“我们没有证据
"Well, we have no proof.
我们只有这个”
"All we have is this."
不
No.
那真是深奥
Wow, that's deep.
所以就是生命吧
So, it's like life after birth.
充满希望
Hopeful.
你到底想要什么？
All right, what do you want?
你为何来这里？
Why are you here?
你的陈词滥调我都听腻了
I've heard all of your platitudes.
我都明白了
I got them, I know.
“她去了更好的地方
"She's in a better place."
冥冥中自有主宰”
And, "This is all a part of a master plan."
也听过了
Heard that one, too.
接下来是我最喜欢的
Here's my favorite.
“上帝从天上看下来，看见了一朵最美丽的玫瑰花
"God looked down and saw the most beautiful rose,
太美丽了，所以他摘下来
"so beautiful that he picked it
放在天堂里陪伴他”
"to have it in Heaven all for Himself."
然后就是关于科学，生物中心主义
Then there's the science, biocentrism,
我们在无数宇宙中诞生和死去
and we're all living and dying in infinite universes
同时间
all at the same time.
还有宗教
And then the religion,
基督教和救赎
the Christians and their salvation,
佛教及其轮回之说，还有印度教及其圣礼
and the Buddhists and their Samsara, and the Hindus and their 41 st sacrament.
特别忘不了那些诗句
And can't forget the poetry.
噢，那些诗句
Oh, the poetry.
“死并不像一般人所想像的
"To die is different from what anyone supposed
而是更幸运”
"and luckier."
[Walt Whitman - Song of Myself]
惠特曼
Whitman.
“怒斥吧
And, "Rage...
怒斥光的消逝
"Rage against the dying of the light.
年迈的智者深知黑暗必将来临”
"Though wise men at their end know dark is right."
[Dylan Thomas - Do Not Go Gentle into that Good Night]
托马斯，然后…
Thomas. And then...
“划呀划，划小船，缓缓顺流下
"Row, row, row your boat gently down the stream
开心呀，开心呀，开心呀，开心吧
"Merrily, merrily, merrily, merrily
人生不过一场梦”
"Life is but a dream"
我知道了
I got it.
我全都明白了！
I got it!
全都在说你是生命的必经的阶段
It all basically says that you're a natural part of life,
我们不该恨你和害怕你
we shouldn't hate you, we shouldn't fear you.
我猜我们该坦然接受你对吧？
I guess we should just accept you, right?
就这样？
That's it?
我明白了，不过我想说
I get it. Here's the thing.
这全都是读书人的一派胡言而已
It's all a bunch of intellectual bullshit
因为她此时此地不在
because she's not here holding my fucking hand.
你好，霍华德
Hi, Howard.
你又要哭了吗？
You gonna cry again?
你不喜欢我伤心时的模样？
You don't like it when I'm sad?
- 你不是整天都伤心的吗？ - 当然不是
- Ah, aren't you always sad?  - No.
我可以有其他心情，我可以是快乐
No, I can be other things. I can be happy.
我可以是意想不到和不可预测的
I can be unexpected and unpredictable...
还有性感，温馨，神秘…
...and sexy and warm and mysterious and...
和窝心
And home.
我可以很窝心，霍华德，你记得吗？
I can be home, Howard, you remember?
你记得我吗？
Do you remember me?
听着，那些什么“生命的基本”，留给跟别人说吧
Listen. All the "fabric of life" bullshit, save that for somebody else.
那不是胡说的
It's not bullshit.
我知道你不相信我，但你要给我另一次机会
I know you don't believe me, but you have to trust me.
相信你？
Trust you?
- 相信你？ - 对！
- Trust you?  - Yes!
我相信过你啊！
I did trust you!
然而你背叛了我！
And you betrayed me!
我曾经每天都在她的双眸中看到你
I saw you every day in her eyes,
还有在她的笑声中
and I heard you in her voice when she laughed,
还有当她叫我“爸爸”时，我感觉到你在我里面
and I felt you inside of me when she called me "Daddy."
然后你背叛了我！
And you betrayed me!
你伤透了我的心
You broke my heart.
不
No.
我在万物当中
I'm in all of it.
我是黑暗同时也是曙光
I'm the darkness and the light,
我是太阳般温暖同时也是风暴般难以预测
I'm the sunshine and the storm.
你说对了
Yes, you're right.
我存在在她的笑声中
I was there in her laugh,
但我现在也在你的伤痛之中
but I'm also here now in your pain.
我是万物的起因
I'm the reason for everything.
我是唯一的“原因”
I am the only "why."
别以为没了我可以生活，霍华德
Don't try and live without me, Howard.
拜托不要
Please don't.
与宏盟集团的协议快要达成了
The deal with Omnicom's almost done.
那霍华德那边呢？
What about Howard?
他们也注意到现在的情况
Well, they're aware of the situation
但我们仍然要证明霍华德
but we still have to prove that Howard's ability to vote
没有投票的能力
is, uh, compromised.
我难以相信变成了这个局面
I can't believe it's come down to this.
对，但还是得相信
Yeah, well, believe it.
我们星期四有个跟委员会讨论霍华德能力的会议
We have a competency meeting with the board set for Thursday.
我们来这里是给你一个解释的机会
We're here to give you a chance to explain this.
霍华德，影片中你在做什么？
Howard, what are you doing in this video?
我不在乎时间
I do not care about time.
这是监禁
This is a prison sentence!
我不想要你的所谓礼物！
I don't want your gift!
你在做什么，霍华德？
What are you doing, Howard?
因为你拿走了她的时间
Because you took hers.
霍华德？
Howard?
你又要哭吗？
You gonna cry again?
你不是整天都伤心的吗？
Aren't you always sad?
这段呢？
What about here?
听着，那些什么“生命的基本”
Listen. All the "fabric of life" bullshit,
留给跟别人说吧
save that for somebody else.
相信你？
Trust you?
我相信过你啊！
I did trust you!
我把一切托付给你
I committed everything to you
而你背叛了我！
and you betrayed me!
我曾经每天都在她的双眸中看到你
I saw you every day in her eyes,
还有在她的笑声中
and I heard you in her voice when she laughed.
我感觉到你在我里面
And I felt you inside of me...
霍华德？
Howard?
当她叫我爸爸时
...when she called me "Daddy."
霍华德？
Howard?
你伤透了我的心
You broke my heart.
霍华德，我需要你的答覆，你在跟谁说话？
Howard, I need you to answer me. Who are you shouting at here?
你的陈词滥调我都听过了，我全都明白了
I've heard all of your platitudes. I got them, I know.
不是“谁”
Um, it's not "who."
冥冥中自有主宰
And, "This is all a part of a master plan."
抱歉，什么？
I'm sorry, what?
我明白了
I got it.
霍华德，你说了什么？
Howard, did you say something?
我不是在跟人说话
I'm not talking to people.
很明显，那你在跟谁说话？
Well, that's obvious. Who are you talking to?
霍华德，你在跟谁说话？
Howard, who are you talking to?
够了
That's enough. It's enough.
谢谢
Thank you.
我想，你指出了重点
You made the point, I think.
把它关闭吧
Just turn it off.
你聘请人去跟踪我？
You hired people to follow me?
去录影？
Make video?
不，那不是我们最初的打算
No, that wasn't the initial intention.
对，我们这样做了
No, we did.
对
Yeah, we did.
我们除了那还做了很多，霍华德
We did a lot more than that, Howard.
霍华德，很抱歉
Howard, I'm so sorry.
我们觉得…
We felt like...
我们不知道还可以做什么
We didn't know what else to do.
- 克莱尔  - 不，我不能再这样做了
- Claire.  - No. I can't do this anymore.
我不能，惠特
I can't do this anymore, Whit.
听着，我真的…
Listen, I really...
我甚至没想过那会行得通
I didn't even think that it was gonna work.
- 真的，坦白说，我…  - 克莱尔，克莱尔，克莱尔
- Really, honestly, I...  - Claire. Claire. Claire.
我很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
- 好了好了  - 霍华德…
- All right, all right, all right.  - Howard...
我很显现地不在状态
I'm obviously not in the right state of mind.
可能我们所有人都不在状态
Maybe none of us are.
你以为我没留意吗？
You think I haven't noticed?
我是说，克莱尔
I mean, Claire,
你奉献了你整生给这公司
you dedicated your entire life to this agency.
你让我们成为一家人
You made us your family
当你有能力出去闯一番事业的时候
when you could have been starting your own.
还有，你一直费尽心思
And, uh, you've been absolutely killing yourself,
帮我掩饰
covering for me,
很感谢你
and I appreciate that.
谢谢
Thank you.
还有你，西蒙
And, Simon,
你尽力不让任何人知道
you've done your best to hide it from everyone,
但我知道你的过去
but I know your history.
我怀疑我在将一个无可挽救的局面
And I suspect I'm making an already impossible situation
弄得更糟糕
even worse for you.
我向你保证
I promise you,
我一日还在
as long as I am here,
你的家庭都会得到照料
your family will be cared for.
谢谢
Thank you.
惠特
Whit.
我最好的朋友
Best friend I've ever had.
但我对你很失望
But I'm disappointed in you, man.
我不是指这个
I mean, not for... Not for this.
不是这个
Not for this.
你不需要她的允许才当她的父亲
You don't need her permission to be her father.
埃里森是你生命中最美好的事
Allison's the best thing you got happening in this world,
人生苦短，及时行乐
and tomorrow's not promised.
听到了吗？
Do you hear me?
你们做了件正确的事
You guys did the right thing.
我想我们的公司继续运作
I want our agency to survive.
总有些事要继续吧
Something should.
好了
All right, um...
我会签署的
I'll sign the papers now.
你同意售卖股份
Your approval of the sale.
另一份呢？
Uh, the other one?
你给了六通电话都要让我签署的那份呢？
The one you called me six times to have me sign.
我认为你会一同带来
Um, I assume you have it here with you.
抱歉，Howord
I am sorry, Howard.
这是件正确的事
This is the right thing.
我告诉你们，这是件正确的事
I'm telling you, this is the right thing.
抱歉
Excuse me.
第二份文件是什么？
What was that second piece of paper?
霍华德把他的部份所有权放到他女儿名下的信托基金
Howard put some of his ownership into a trust in his daughter's name.
那只是份法律证书表明她已经不在了
It's just a legal certificate saying she's no longer with us.
我想我需要喝一杯
I think I need a drink.
你还好吗？
Are you okay?
他们说天堂里时间的流动
"They say that the time in Heaven
跟我们世界比较起来
"is compared to the blink of an eye
就是一眨眼的工夫
"for us on this Earth.
有时候我会觉得亚当
"Sometimes I think of Adam
正在一遍长满花草的美丽田园里奔跑
"running through a beautiful field of wild flowers.
[寻找你的精子捐赠者]
他会是那么快乐，忘我地奔跑
"He's so happy, completely caught up in what he's doing.
然后他会回过头来
"But then he looks back
像他平常跑在我前面时会做的
"like he used to do when he ran ahead of me
在机场或市场，哪里都好
"in airports or malls or wherever.
然后他会对着我笑
"And he smiles."
天啊
Jesus.
因为他的一眨眼已经是我的余生了
"Because the blink of his eye was the rest of my life
而我还在他背后
"and I'm right there behind him."
无论如何，这是我的第一次
Anyway, it's a first draft.
很美丽的故事
It's beautiful.
真的很美丽
Really beautiful.
还有人想要分享吗？
Does anybody else wanna say anything?
那好吧，我想今晚就到此为止了
Okay, I guess that's all for tonight.
谢谢
Thank you.
抱歉
Sorry, sorry.
哟
Yo!
简直不能相信你让我来到这街区
I can't believe you made me come into this neighborhood
身上还带着两万现金
carrying $20,000 in cash.
你要用来做什么？
What are you gonna do with it?
你应该为你的演艺学院储起来
You should put it aside for acting school.
你很有演技
You were really good.
我要用来买狡诈家药物
Mmm. I'm gonna use it to buy designer drugs.
那也行
Or that, too.
对
Yeah.
嘿，你将会是一个好妈妈
Hey, you gonna make a good mom one day.
是吗？
Yeah?
是的，那是宣传单张里没说的
Yeah, well, that's pretty much not in the cards.
我以前决定了反对科学
I decided against the science
看来时间终于找上门了
and it seems time finally caught up with me.
以前有个卖书套的人在一百八十七号街给了我一本叫《美丽新世界的》书
There was this dust dealer up on 187th who gave me Brave New World.
那本书读起来令人乐而忘返
That book turned hours into seconds.
他是我的父亲
He was my father.
还有个无家可归的女人
And there was this homeless woman
在大学高地桥下生活
who lived under the University Heights bridge.
她的名字是弗洛拉
Her name was Flora.
她精神失常，但她说了最有趣的故事给我
She was batshit crazy, but she told me the greatest stories.
她是我的母亲
She was my mother.
听着，克莱尔
See, Claire,
你的孩子们不一定要由你生出来
your children don't have to come from you.
他们可以是让你经过历练
They go through you.
所以我不会那么快就考虑跟时间投降
So, I wouldn't consider the battle with time over just yet.
我以为时间不是直线的
I thought time wasn't linear.
我以为它是幻像
I thought it was an illusion.
或者一切都只是废话而已，克莱尔
Maybe that was just bullshit, Claire.
或者那只是演戏
Maybe that was just acting.
- 嗨，埃里森  - 我们快走吧
- Hey, Allison.  - Come on, let's go.
别这样，埃里森！
Oh. Come on. Allison!
我晚点跟你们会面
I'll meet you guys there.
你知道我不想跟你说话
I don't wanna talk to you. You know that.
别烦我
Leave me alone.
不，我永远不会留下你
No. I won't leave you alone.
- 不会吗？ - 不会
- No?  - No.
我知道你在生我的气，那很正常
I know you're angry at me, and that's okay.
我承受得到
I can take it.
但我们需要好好谈谈，因为那就是家人会做的事
But we gotta talk about it because that's what you do in a family.
所以我每天都会来并在你的朋友面前让你显得尴尬
So I'm gonna come here every day and embarrass you in front of your friends
直到你跟我说话为止
until you talk to me.
所以你打算跟踪我？
So you're gonna stalk me?
对，基本上是
Well... Yes, basically.
那如果我申请限制令呢？
Well, what if I get a restraining order?
我不认为你有能力可以做到
Well, I don't think you're gonna be able to do that.
我会让妈妈替我付钱
Well, I'll get Mom to pay for it.
跟你说下，它们是免费的
Well, for your information, they're free.
那我会让你替我付钱
Well, then I'll get you to pay for it.
我真的很爱你
I really love you.
妈妈说你令那个字变质了
Mom says you butcher that word.
不在我跟你说的时候
Not when I say it to you.
听着
Look...
我没能力带着你飞到缅因州吃午餐
I can't fly you to Maine for lunch
或者用驾着特斯拉来接你
or get you picked up in a Tesla
[安娜·温图尔：时尚杂志编辑]
或者让你到安娜·温图尔旗下实习
and take you to your internship with Anna Wintour
或者他们在这街区会做的事
or whatever the hell they do in this neighborhood.
但我想我们可以坐在公园的长椅上
But I think that you and me can sit on a park bench
说说笑，享受一段美好时光
and tell jokes and have a pretty good time.
我不能相信你会跟踪我
I can't believe you're gonna stalk me.
但…
But, um...
只是说下，明天只有半天课
Just so you know, tomorrow's a half-day.
那我明天也会在这里
Well, I'll be here then.
嗨
Hey.
你的
Here you are.
我等了别人给我的肯定很久了
I've been waiting a long time for my moment for validation,
这就是我要的
and this was it.
一位在角落不起眼，也不拍掌的观众
An audience of one, in secret, with no applause.
我跟我的妻子说了
I told my wife.
那她怎样反应？
Oh, how did it go?
她早就知道了
She knew.
她在做准备了
She's getting ready for it.
当我还年轻时，我经常想
You know, when I was younger, I used to think,
你真的想活到一百岁吗？
you really wanna live to be 100 years old?
像干瘪了的葡萄干一样
You know, like a shriveled up raisin.
而我现在会给的答覆是
And the answer to that now
对
is yes.
因为我的儿子将会是七十岁
Because my son would be 70,
他的儿子会是四十岁
his son would be 40,
他的儿子会是十岁
and his son would be 10.
而我就能成为那个人
And I would be the man, you know.
老爸的角色
Pops.
真想成为啊
Could get used to that, you know.
再见，老爸
See you around, Pops.
我真想去看你的话剧
I wish I could be here to see the play.
不，那话剧经过是次早就没了
Oh, no, no. The play is dead after all this.
但谁知道呢
But you never know,
没什么是死的，如果以正确的角度去看的话
nothing's ever really dead if you look at it right.
嗨
Hey.
今晚是平安夜
Uh, it's Christmas Eve.
而你只独身一人
And you're alone.
我自愿的
By choice.
我可以破坏你独处的时间吗？
Can I ruin that?
[最好的妈妈]
你刚才在哭
You've been crying.
我刚才在看我为我女儿拍的影片
I was watching a video I took of my daughter.
她在跟她的父亲跳舞
She's dancing with her father in it.
我能给你看吗，霍华德？
Can I show it to you, Howard?
我女儿叫奥利维亚
My daughter's name was Olivia.
她因为一种罕有的脑癌而过世
She died of a rare form of brain cancer
叫胶质母细胞瘤
known as Glioblastoma Multiforme,
或简称“GBM”
or GBM for short.
她当时六岁
She was six years old.
你的女儿叫什么，霍华德？
What was your daughter's name, Howard?
如果我们可以重新相遇一次就好了
"If only we could be strangers again."
你的女儿叫什么，霍华德？
What was your daughter's name, Howard?
我不能…
I can't.
I... I can't.
转快点！
Swing me faster!
快点快点，爸爸！
Faster, Daddy! Faster!
霍华德…
Howard...
我是只小鸟
I feel like a bird.
说出她的名字
Say her name.
她叫什么？
What was her name?
奥利维亚
Olivia.
她叫奥利维亚
Her name was Olivia.
她怎过身的？
How did she die?
她患了一种叫胶质母细胞瘤的罕有癌症
She had a rare form of cancer called Glioblastoma Multiforme,
或简称“GBM”
or GBM for short.
她当时才六岁
She was only six years old.
她叫奥利维亚
Her name was Olivia.
她患了一种叫胶质母细胞瘤的罕有癌症
She had a rare form of cancer called Glioblastoma Multiforme,
或简称“GBM”
or GBM for short.
她当时才六岁
She was only six years old.
我们宝贝的名字叫奥利维亚
Our baby's name was Olivia.
她当时才六岁
She was only six years old.
你们在做什么？
What are you guys doing?
你准备好了吗？
You ready? You ready?
去吧！
Go, go!
现在我们由头再做一次
Now we start all over again.
你准备好了吗？
You ready?
我们由头再做一次
We start all over again.
你要失去一个亲人吗？
Are you losing somebody?
什么？
I'm sorry?
你要失去谁？
Who are you losing?
我的女儿
Um, my daughter.
记着留意附属的美丽
Just make sure you notice the collateral beauty.